GYEONGGI POLICE WITH SAFETY, ORDER, AND RESPONSIBILITY
안전과 질서, 책임을 다하는 경기경찰
MISSING PERSON NAME: AN YU-YEON
실종자 이름 : 안유연
That's too blurry.
너무 흐릿해요.
That won't be enough
그것만으로는 충분하지 않을 거야
for us to confirm if the woman next to him
옆에 여자가 있는지 확인하기 위해
is the missing woman or not.
실종된 여자인지 아닌지.
You guys have good eyes. Take a closer look.
너희들은 좋은 눈을 가지고 있다. 자세히 살펴보세요.
If it were the older cameras, it would've been more blurry.
만약 오래된 카메라였다면 더 흐릿했을 것입니다.
Young-soo kept pushing for them too.
영수도 계속 밀어붙였다.
It's blurry,
흐릿해요.
but the vehicle was spotted
하지만 차량이 발견됐어요
around the locations where the women went missing.
그 여성들이 실종된 장소 주변에요 .
Detective Nam.
남 형사님.
-Did you run the license plate? -I put in a request.
-번호판은 달았나요? -요청을 넣었어요.
We used the security cameras to track him on the same night.
우리는 같은 날 밤 그를 추적하기 위해 보안 카메라를 사용했습니다 .
But we couldn't track him after the 5km mark.
하지만 5km 지점 이후에는 그를 추적할 수 없었습니다 .
We can suspect that he probably
우리는 그가 아마도
went to someplace secluded.
한적한 곳으로 갔다.
If he's our guy,
그 사람이 우리 남자라면,
he probably abandoned the body right away.
아마 바로 시신을 버렸을 겁니다.
Yes?
예?
Woo Ho-sung?
우호성?
Okay.
좋아요.
A 38-year-old man, Woo Ho-sung.
38세 남자 우호성입니다.
They faxed us the information of the vehicle owner.
그들은 차량 소유자의 정보를 우리에게 팩스로 보냈습니다 .
Okay.
좋아요.
The vehicle owner is Woo Ho-sung, a 38-year-old man.
차량 소유자는 우호성( 38)씨.
He works at an acupressure massage parlor.
그는 지압 마사지 가게에서 일합니다.
Why does he look so normal? This is so creepy.
그 사람은 왜 이렇게 평범해 보이는 걸까요? 정말 소름끼친다.
Those who look normal are good at scamming people.
평범해 보이는 사람이 사기를 잘 치는군요.
Shouldn't we check his alibi first?
먼저 그의 알리바이를 확인해 보아야 하지 않을까?
I'll take Detective Nam with me.
남형사님은 제가 데리고 갈게요.
-Okay. -Then can you pay attention
-좋아요. -그럼 주목해 주시겠어요?
to his reaction when you meet him for the first time?
그를 처음 만났을 때 그의 반응은 어땠나요 ?
-Sure. -I already know.
-확신하는. -이미 알고 있어요.
I bet he'll say he didn't do it.
나는 그가 그것을하지 않았다고 말할 것이라고 확신합니다.
He'll probably deny everything
그 사람은 아마 모든 걸 부정할 거야
even if he did it.
그가 그랬다고 해도.
Right. He'll deny it.
오른쪽. 그는 그것을 거부할 것이다.
So Captain Yoon,
그러니까 윤 선장님,
I need you to check if he gets angry or remains calm when you question him.
당신이 그에게 질문할 때 그가 화를 내는지, 아니면 침착함을 유지하는지 확인해주세요 .
Pay attention to the subtle changes in his attitude or the way he talks.
그의 태도나 말하는 방식의 미묘한 변화에 주의를 기울이십시오 .
It will help us with our interrogation strategy.
그것은 우리 의 심문 전략에 도움이 될 것입니다.
You got it.
맞아요.
To women, he's still a stranger.
여자들에게 그는 여전히 낯설다.
No matter how approachable he seems,
그 사람이 아무리 접근하기 쉬운 것처럼 보이더라도
they would still be hesitant to get in his car, right?
그들은 여전히 ​​그의 차에 타는 것을 주저할 것입니다. 그렇죠?
Right.
오른쪽.
And women tend to be more cautious, especially at night,
그리고 여자들은 특히 밤에 더 조심하는 경향이 있습니다 .
no matter how kind they seem.
아무리 친절해 보이더라도.
If he didn't force them to get in,
만약 그가 강제로 들어가지 않았다면,
it's likely that he made them feel guilty
그 사람이 그들에게 죄책감을 느끼게 했을 가능성이 있어
about turning down his kindness.
그의 친절을 거절하는 것에 대해.
He made them feel guilty by pretending to be kind?
친절한 척 해서 죄책감을 느끼게 만든 걸까요 ?
This bastard is unbelievable.
이 놈은 믿을 수가 없어요.
This guy could skip town for all we know.
이 사람은 우리가 아는 한 마을을 건너뛸 수도 있습니다.
-So be careful. -Okay.
-그러니 조심해. -좋아요.
We'll be back.
우리는 돌아올거야.
Call us if there's anything.
무슨 일 있으면 전화하세요.
-Okay. -We'll call you.
-좋아요. -전화드리겠습니다.
-Thank you. -Sure.
-감사합니다. -확신하는.
I think this is the place.
나는 이것이 장소라고 생각한다.
-I'll check if there's an exit. -Okay.
-출구가 있는지 확인해 볼게요. -좋아요.
ROYAL ACUPRESSURE, ANSAN, GYEONGGI
로얄지압, 경기 안산
None, right?
없음, 그렇죠?
This is the only exit.
이것이 유일한 출구입니다.
Okay. Let's go inside.
좋아요. 안에 들어 가자.
-Hello. -Welcome.
-안녕하세요. -환영.
Do you have an appointment?
약속이 있습니까?
We're from Wide-Area Investigation Squad.
우리는 광역수사대 출신이다.
Our business isn't illegal.
우리 사업은 불법이 아닙니다.
We're here to see Mr. Woo Ho-sung.
우호성 선생님을 만나러 왔습니다.
He's here, right?
그 사람 여기 있어요, 그렇죠?
Why do the police want to see him?
경찰은 왜 그를 만나고 싶어 하는 걸까요?
Could you bring him out?
그 사람을 데리고 나가 주시겠어요?
He's with a customer now.
그는 지금 고객과 함께 있습니다.
Then we'll wait here.
그럼 여기서 기다리겠습니다.
But your customers will come and go. You're okay with that, right?
하지만 고객은 왔다가 갈 것입니다. 괜찮으세요?
Please wait.
기다리세요.
Sure.
확신하는.
There.
거기.
Is that a wig?
그거 가발이에요?
I can't see his face clearly.
나는 그의 얼굴을 명확하게 볼 수 없습니다.
How do his hands look to you?
그 사람의 손이 당신에게 어떻게 보이나요?
You wanted to see me?
나를 보고 싶었나요?
Mr. Woo Ho-sung?
씨. 우호성?
Yes. That's me.
예. 그게 나야.
Could we step out for a moment? We have some questions.
잠시 나가볼까요? 몇 가지 질문이 있습니다.
We can talk here.
우리는 여기서 얘기할 수 있어요.
Let's do this outside.
이건 밖에서 해보자.
No. I'm sorry.
아냐 미안해.
My customer is waiting for me inside.
내 고객이 안에서 나를 기다리고 있습니다.
It's fine. Let's talk here.
괜찮아. 여기서 얘기하자.
Where were you on February 23 from 7 p.m. to 10 p.m.?
2월 23일 오후 7시부터 오후 10시까지 어디에 계셨나요 ?
And what were you doing that day?
그리고 그날 당신은 무엇을 하고 있었나요?
Why do you ask?
왜 물어보나요?
We need to verify your alibi
당신의 알리바이를 확인해야 해요
for a case we're working on.
우리가 진행 중인 사건에 대해요.
Did I do something wrong,
내가 뭐 잘못 했어요,
Detective Yoon?
윤 형사?
On the night of February 23,
2월 23일 밤,
a woman in her 20s went missing in Gunpo.
군포에서 20대 여성이 실종됐다.
That's the case we're investigating now.
지금 우리가 조사하고 있는 사건이 바로 그 사건입니다.
And your vehicle was caught
그리고 당신 차량이 잡혔어요
on the security camera
보안 카메라에
in the area where the victim was.
피해자가 있던 지역에서.
My goodness. I didn't know about that.
이럴 수가. 나는 그것에 대해 몰랐습니다.
February 23… Was that Thursday?
2월 23일??? 그날이 목요일이었나요?
It was last Friday.
지난 금요일이었습니다.
I see. Friday. Then, on February 23,
알겠어요. 금요일. 그러다가 2월 23일,
my shift must have ended before 5 p.m.
내 근무 시간은 오후 5시 이전에 끝났나 봐요
Right?
오른쪽?
Yes. That's correct. Take a look.
예. 맞습니다. 구경하다.
WOO HO-SUNG
우호성
-I see. -I had dinner around here
-알겠어요. -저녁은 이 근처에서 먹었어요
with my girlfriend. And then I went home.
내 여자친구랑. 그리고 나는 집에 갔다.
And my girlfriend also happens to live in Gunpo.
그리고 제 여자친구도 군포에 살고 있어요.
There are dangerous people in the world.
세상에는 위험한 사람들이 있습니다.
So I can never let her go alone. I always drop her off.
그래서 나는 결코 그녀를 혼자 보낼 수 없습니다. 나는 항상 그녀를 내려준다.
And I drove her home that night as always.
그리고 나는 그날 밤 언제나처럼 그녀를 집으로 데려다주었습니다.
I don't remember the exact time,
정확한 시간은 기억나지 않지만,
but I was home around 10 p.m.
하지만 나는 밤 10시쯤 집에 돌아왔어
Could we get your girlfriend's
네 여자친구를 구할 수 있을까?
phone number?
전화 번호?
I can't.
나는 할 수 없다.
Am I obligated by law to give you her number?
내가 당신에게 그녀의 전화번호를 알려줄 법적 의무가 있나요 ?
I don't want my girlfriend to worry.
여자친구가 걱정하는 걸 원하지 않아요.
Then how about this?
그럼 이건 어때요?
You can check my alibi at the restaurant we went to that day.
저의 알리바이는 그날 갔던 레스토랑에서 확인하실 수 있습니다 .
I made a reservation before going.
가기전에 예약하고 갔어요
Check it yourself.
직접 확인해 보세요.
What if we go there and ask them, but…
거기 가서 물어보면 어떨까요???
Go check first.
먼저 가서 확인해 보세요.
If you still can't confirm my alibi,
아직도 내 알리바이를 확인할 수 없다면,
I'll give you her number then.
그럼 내가 그 사람 전화번호를 알려줄게.
Is that all?
그게 다야?
I have to get back in.
다시 들어가야 해요.
Thank you for your cooperation.
도와 주셔서 감사합니다.
You're welcome.
천만에요.
-Thank you. Take care. -You too.
-감사합니다. 잘 지내세요. -너도.
I'm so sorry to keep you waiting.
기다리게 해서 정말 죄송합니다.
I'll give you ten extra minutes
10분만 더 드릴게요
to make up for it.
그것을 만회하기 위해.
If we combed through the entire area but didn't find additional bodies,
전 지역을 샅샅이 뒤졌으나 추가 시신을 찾지 못했다면,
it means he buried them elsewhere.
그것은 그가 그것들을 다른 곳에 묻었다는 것을 의미합니다.
Like the sixth case, it must be a place that can't easily be found.
여섯 번째 경우처럼 쉽게 찾을 수 없는 곳이겠지 .
We have to ask him about it when we interrogate him.
우리가 그를 심문할 때 그것에 대해 물어봐야 합니다 .
The sixth victim, Yoon Jin-sil, was abducted in Anyang.
여섯 번째 피해자 윤진실씨가 안양에서 납치됐다.
Then Woo Ho-sung buried her on his way home to Ansan.
이어 우호성은 안산으로 돌아가는 길에 그녀를 묻었다.
And his place isn't far from the bank where money was withdrawn
그리고 그의 집은 돈이 인출된 은행에서 멀지 않은 곳에 있습니다.
from the account of An Yu-yeon, the seventh victim.
7번째 피해자 안유연씨의 계정에서 .
He doesn't live far from where the other victims went missing,
그는 다른 피해자들이 실종된 곳 에서 멀지 않은 곳에 살고 있습니다 .
assuming that he was driving.
그가 운전을 했다고 가정하자.
And his vehicle was caught on camera,
그리고 그의 차량이 카메라에 포착됐는데요,
heading in the same direction that the culprit must've gone.
범인이 갔을 방향과 같은 방향으로 가고 있어요 .
Woo Ho-sung is our prime suspect.
우호성이 유력 용의자다.
Woo Ho-sung, that scumbag.
우호성, 그 쓰레기.
It's possible he's also committed insurance scams.
그는 또한 보험 사기를 저질렀을 가능성이 있습니다 .
I'm Detective Nam from the Gyeonggi Provincial Police Agency.
경기지방경찰청 남형사입니다 .
Did someone named Woo Ho-sung have a reservation here?
우호성이라는 분이 여기 예약하셨나요?
Woo Ho-sung? What's his phone number?
우호성? 그 사람 전화번호는 뭐죠?
That is him.
바로 그 사람입니다.
WOO HO-SUNG
우호성
Yes, Gyeonggi Provincial Police Agency…
응, 경기지방경찰청???
It's Detective Yoon.
윤형사입니다.
Hang on. Let me put you on speaker.
잠깐만요. 스피커로 연결해 드리겠습니다.
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
Does he have an alibi?
그 사람에겐 알리바이가 있나요?
He said he had dinner
저녁을 먹었다고 하더군요
with his girlfriend that evening.
그날 저녁 그의 여자친구와 함께.
After that, he drove her home.
그 후 그는 그녀를 집으로 데려갔습니다.
Detective Nam went to the restaurant to check.
남형사는 확인을 위해 식당에 갔다.
What's his attitude like?
그의 태도는 어떤가요?
He seemed self-assured.
그는 자신감이 있어 보였다.
And he's confident.
그리고 그는 자신감이 있습니다.
He also seemed relaxed.
그도 편안해 보였습니다.
He sounds polite and has good manners,
그 사람 말은 예의 바르고 매너도 좋고,
so I can see the victims letting their guard down easily
피해자들이 쉽게 방심하는 걸 볼 수 있게
after a few awkward moments upon encountering a stranger.
낯선 사람을 만나 어색한 순간을 보낸 후 .
You haven't checked his car, have you?
당신은 그 사람 차를 확인하지 않았죠?
We can't search his car without a warrant.
영장 없이는 그의 차를 수색할 수 없습니다.
If we aren't careful, he may try to destroy evidence,
조심하지 않으면 증거인멸을 시도할 수도 있고,
so we'll wait until he gets off work and check naturally
그러니까 그 사람 퇴근할 때까지 기다리 면서 자연스럽게 확인하자.
when he gets in his car.
그가 차에 타면.
How did it go?
어떻게 됐나요?
He was at the restaurant that evening.
그는 그날 저녁 레스토랑에 있었습니다.
He did have a reservation under his name, and I checked the CCTV footage too.
자기 이름으로 예약이 되어 있었고, CCTV 영상도 확인해 봤습니다.
The woman he was with wasn't the one who went missing.
실종된 사람은 함께 있던 여자가 아니었습니다.
I think it was his girlfriend.
내 생각엔 그의 여자친구였던 것 같아.
-Goodbye. -Bye.
-안녕히 가세요. -안녕.
Wait, Ho-sung.
잠깐만요, 호성 씨.
What did the detectives want?
형사들이 원하는 것은 무엇이었나요?
I think there was a misunderstanding.
오해가 있었던 것 같아요.
How could they suspect you, of all people?
그 사람들이 어떻게 당신을 의심할 수 있겠습니까?
-It's all cleared up now. -Good.
-이제 다 해결됐어요. -좋은.
He's different from those who don't have
그 사람은 가진 게 없는 사람과는 달라
the ability to lure their victims or those who launch random motiveless attacks.
피해자나 동기 없는 무작위 공격을 시작하는 사람들을 유인하는 능력입니다.
On top of his expensive car and likable face,
값비싼 차 와 호감가는 얼굴 에
he has a way with words. He used all those things
그는 말을 잘합니다. 그는 그 모든 것을 사용했습니다
to find and lure his victims.
희생자를 찾아 유인하기 위해.
He knows that it works.
그는 그것이 효과가 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
That's where Woo Ho-sung's confidence comes from.
우호성의 자신감은 바로 여기에서 나온다.
That's right.
좋아요.
Yes, Wide-Area Investigation Squad…
응, 광역수사대???
Hey.
여기요.
Hold on.
기다리다.
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
We have confirmed his alibi that he had dinner
저녁식사를 했다는 알리바이를 확인했습니다
with his girlfriend that evening.
그날 저녁 여자친구와 함께.
Do we know what else he did that night?
그날 밤 그가 또 무엇을 했는지 우리는 알고 있나요?
Detective Moon at Anyang Station looked into it,
안양역에서 문 형사가 이를 살펴보더니,
but there was nothing on his call log after 7 p.m. that evening.
하지만 그날 저녁 7시 이후에는 그의 통화 기록에 아무것도 없었습니다 .
We checked all the cameras near his home,
우리는 그의 집 근처에 있는 모든 카메라를 확인했습니다.
and he got home at around 1:00 a.m.
그는 오전 1시쯤 집에 돌아왔습니다
He told us that he got home at around 10 p.m.
밤 10시쯤 집에 왔다고 하더군요
We need to go and check. I wish we could search his house now.
가서 확인해 봐야 해요. 지금 당장 그의 집을 수색할 수 있으면 좋겠습니다.
Our priority is securing evidence.
우리의 우선순위는 증거 확보입니다.
If we put in a request for a search and seizure warrant now,
지금 압수수색영장을 청구한다면 ,
the prosecutors will laugh at us.
검찰이 우리를 비웃을 것이다.
-It won't be issued. -Chief Park.
-발급되지 않습니다. -박과장.
We'll wait here until Woo Ho-sung gets off work
우호성이 퇴근할 때까지 여기서 기다릴게요
and ask him to voluntarily come into the station.
그리고 그에게 자발적으로 역으로 와달라고 부탁하세요.
I'll call you back.
다시 전화하겠습니다.
Goodness.
선량.
Even if we request a warrant now,
지금 당장 영장을 청구하더라도
we won't get it tonight.
오늘 밤엔 못 받을 거야.
Okay, fine.
좋아.
I'll speak with Superintendent Heo.
허 교육감과 통화하겠습니다.
I'm getting a bad feeling.
기분이 나빠요.
NAME: WOO HO-SUNG
이름: 우호성
We need a search and seizure warrant for Woo Ho-sung's vehicle and residence.
우호성의 차량과 주거지에 대한 압수수색영장이 필요하다 .
We must secure evidence as soon as possible.
하루빨리 증거를 확보해야 합니다 .
It's also possible he committed insurance scams in the past.
과거에도 보험사기를 저질렀을 가능성도 있다 .
Insurance scams? What did he do?
보험사기? 그가 무슨 짓을 한거야?
In 2005,
2005년에는
his wife and mother-in-law died in a fire.
그의 아내와 시어머니가 화재로 사망했습니다.
The life insurance payout he got was 400 million won in total.
그가 받은 생명보험료는 모두 4억 원.
400 million won?
4억 원?
He had signed up for various life insurance policies.
그는 다양한 생명 보험에 가입했습니다 .
But the insurance companies must've deemed it legitimate for him
하지만 보험회사에서는 그것이 그에게 합법적이라고 생각했을 것입니다.
to have received the money.
돈을 받았기 때문이다.
On what grounds are we suspecting him?
우리는 어떤 근거로 그를 의심하는 걸까요?
Even with Gu Young-chun and Nam Ki-Tae, we found evidence in their homes.
구영춘, 남기태에 대해서도 그들의 집에서 증거를 찾았다.
We can't let this guy buy time. Not even another moment.
이 사람에게 시간을 벌게 놔둘 수는 없습니다. 또 다른 순간도 아닙니다.
He'll destroy all the evidence.
그는 모든 증거를 파괴할 것이다.
And this is
그리고 이건
Song Ha-young's profiling report.
송하영 프로파일링 리포트.
GYEONGGI SERIAL MISSING WOMEN CASE PROFILING REPORT
경기 연재물 실종 여성 사건 프로파일링 보고서
Everyone now knows he was instrumental in tracking down Gu Young-chun
이제 그가 구영춘을 추적하는 데 중요한 역할을 했다는 사실은 모두가 알고 있습니다.
and Nam Ki-Tae.
그리고 남기태.
You should submit this along with the request.
요청과 함께 이를 제출해야 합니다 .
Okay, I'll speak with Prosecutor Jang.
좋아요, 장 검사님과 통화하겠습니다.
But I highly doubt that it'll be issued today.
하지만 오늘 발표될지는 매우 의심스럽습니다 .
POMNA DRY CLEANING
폼나 드라이클리닝
Should I go pick up some snacks?
간식 좀 사러 갈까?
I guess you're hungry.
배고픈 것 같아요.
A little.
조금.
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
-Okay. -Wait, Detective Nam.
-좋아요. -잠깐만요, 남 형사님.
ROYAL ACUPRESSURE MASSAGE
로얄 지압 마사지
Mr. Woo Ho-sung!
씨. 우호성!
Do you still have more questions for me?
아직도 나에게 더 궁금한 점이 있나요?
We believe it'll take a while.
우리는 시간이 좀 걸릴 것이라고 믿습니다.
Could we talk
우리 얘기 좀 할 수 있을까?
at the station?
역에서?
Are you arresting me now?
지금 나를 체포하는 겁니까?
Can I see the warrant?
영장을 볼 수 있을까요?
We're asking you to voluntarily come with us.
우리는 여러분이 자발적으로 우리와 함께 가실 것을 요청하고 있습니다.
You may refuse if you don't want to.
원하지 않으시면 거절하실 수도 있습니다.
But if you refuse,
하지만 거절한다면,
it will make us more suspicious of you.
그러면 우리가 당신을 더욱 의심하게 될 것입니다.
We'll continue to keep a close watch on you.
우리는 계속해서 여러분을 면밀히 관찰할 것입니다.
Okay, fine. I'll come in and give a statement.
좋아. 제가 들어가서 성명을 발표하겠습니다.
-Then let's take our-- -The thing is,
-그럼 우리... -문제는,
I was booked back-to-back today, so I'm very tired right now.
오늘 연속 예약이 있어서 지금은 너무 피곤해요.
But I'm off tomorrow,
그런데 내일은 휴가야.
so may I visit the station sometime tomorrow morning?
그럼 내일 아침에 역에 가봐도 될까요 ?
Sure.
확신하는.
Please come…
제발???
to the Gyeonggi Provincial Police Agency.
경기지방경찰청으로.
-If you don't come… -I know.
-안오면??? -알아요.
Why wouldn't I when I did nothing wrong?
내가 잘못한 게 없는데 왜 안 하겠나?
I just have to ask for Detective Yoon, right?
그냥 윤형사한테 물어보면 되는 거 겠죠?
-Yes. -Okay.
-예. -좋아요.
I'll see you tomorrow.
내일 보자.
See you tomorrow.
내일 봐요.
I saw…
나는 보았다???
a photo of him with two dogs in his car.
그의 차에 개 두 마리와 함께 찍은 사진.
And there was a huge teddy bear in the back seat.
그리고 뒷좌석에는 거대한 테디베어가 있었습니다 .
Just as we expected.
우리가 예상했던 대로.
As you said, he's too calm.
네 말대로 그 사람은 너무 조용해.
He'll come tomorrow, right?
그 사람 내일 올 거예요, 그렇죠?
If he flees, it's him for sure, so we can put out an APB.
만약 그가 도망친다면 그 사람이 틀림없으니 우리는 APB를 가동시킬 수 있습니다.
Good work today. Let's call it a night.
오늘 수고했어요. 오늘 밤이라고 부르자.
GYEONGGI PROVINCIAL POLICE AGENCY
경기지방경찰청
I can't stop thinking that he's the culprit.
그 사람이 범인이라는 생각을 멈출 수가 없어요 .
He fits every quality of the suspect we presumed.
그는 우리가 추측한 용의자의 모든 특성에 부합합니다.
He's amicable and has good manners.
그는 우호적이고 매너가 좋습니다.
He even has a nice car.
그 사람은 심지어 좋은 차도 갖고 있어요.
He even has a luring mechanism in his car.
그는 심지어 그의 차에 유인 장치를 가지고 있습니다.
He's under suspicion of arson and insurance fraud.
그는 방화와 보험사기 혐의를 받고 있다.
We have to be open to the possibility he's proficient in arson.
우리는 그가 방화에 능숙할 가능성을 열어두어야 합니다 .
There's no perp who only commits one crime.
한 가지 범죄만 저지르는 범인은 없습니다 .
All we need is the warrant.
우리에게 필요한 것은 영장뿐입니다.
I'm sure he was psychologically pressured.
정신적으로 압박을 받았던 게 틀림없어요.
GYEONGGI PROVINCIAL POLICE AGENCY
경기지방경찰청
Wide-Area Investigation Squad, Gyeonggi Provincial Police Agency.
경기지방경찰청 광역수사대 .
May I speak to Detective Yoon Tae-gu?
윤태구 형사님과 통화할 수 있나요?
Who's calling?
누구세요?
I'm the guy who was supposed to meet her today.
오늘 그 사람 만나기로 한 사람이 바로 나예요 .
If she's in the office, could you put her on?
그녀가 사무실에 있다면, 그녀를 입혀줄 수 있나요?
She's not in the office. If you leave a message, I'll relay it to her.
그녀는 사무실에 없습니다. 메시지를 남겨 주시면 제가 그 사람에게 전달해 드리겠습니다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
-Hello? -In that case, I'll call back…
-안녕하세요? -그럼 제가 다시 전화할게요???
One second, she just came in. I'll put her on right away.
잠깐만요, 방금 들어오셨어요. 바로 입혀드릴게요.
Captain Yoon, it's Woo Ho-sung.
윤대위, 우호성입니다.
I'm on the line. You've reached Yoon Tae-gu.
나는 통화 중입니다. 윤태구까지 오셨습니다.
Hello. This is Woo Ho-sung.
안녕하세요. 우호성 입니다.
Mr. Woo Ho-sung.
씨. 우호성.
Do you take a report like this at Wide-Area Investigation?
광역수사에서도 이런 신고를 받나요 ?
Someone set my car on fire.
누군가 내 차에 불을 질렀어요.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Does Wide-Area Investigation Squad take reports like this?
광역수사대에서는 이런 보고도 받나요?
I thought he was a pretty smart guy, but he wasn't.
나는 그가 꽤 똑똑한 사람이라고 생각했지만 그렇지 않았습니다.
He's just feeling guilty.
그는 단지 죄책감을 느끼고 있을 뿐입니다.
We got the warrant more quickly thanks to his show.
그의 쇼 덕분에 우리는 영장을 더 빨리 받았습니다 .
It's nice.
좋네요.
And the profiling report also played a part.
그리고 프로파일링 보고서 도 한몫했습니다.
WOO HO-SUNG'S HOME
우호성의 집
As of this hour,
이 시간 기준으로,
we will begin the search and seizure of every article in your house.
우리는 당신 집에 있는 모든 물건에 대한 수색과 압수를 시작할 것입니다 .
Also, Woo Ho-sung.
역시 우호성.
You are under emergency arrest for suspicions of abduction.
당신은 납치 혐의로 긴급 체포되었습니다 .
You should be looking for the person who set my car on fire.
내 차에 불을 지른 사람을 찾아야 해요 .
Why are you arresting me?
왜 나를 체포하는 거죠?
You have the right to an attorney,
귀하는 변호사를 선임할 권리가 있습니다.
and you have the right to remain silent.
그리고 당신은 묵비권을 행사할 권리가 있습니다.
Everything you say can and will be
당신이 말하는 모든 것은 될 수 있고 될 것입니다
used to the extreme disadvantage against you in court.
법정에서 당신에게 극도의 불이익을 주는 데 익숙합니다 .
Do you understand?
이해했나요?
Just as I expected, he's confident.
예상했던 대로 그 사람은 자신감이 넘쳤어요.
He knew we'd get suspicious of him for setting his car on fire.
그는 자신의 차에 불을 질렀다면 우리가 그를 의심할 것이라는 것을 알고 있었습니다 .
But he still chose to do that to get rid of the evidence.
하지만 그는 여전히 증거를 없애기 위해 그렇게 하기로 결정했습니다 .
We pressured him to go talk at the police station,
우리는 그에게 경찰서에 가서 이야기하라고 압력을 가했고 ,
so he got anxious and made the wrong choice.
그래서 그는 불안해졌고 잘못된 선택을 했습니다.
I think he wanted to play the victim.
내 생각엔 그가 피해자 역할을 하고 싶었던 것 같아요.
But he was in a hurry, so he must have resorted to something he was used to.
하지만 그는 서두르고 있었기 때문에 익숙한 방법을 사용했을 것입니다.
He forgot that he was under suspicion of arson and insurance fraud.
그는 자신이 방화와 보험사기 혐의를 받고 있다는 사실도 잊어버렸다.
Does he think the police are a joke? As if we wouldn't have looked into it.
경찰이 농담이라고 생각하나요? 마치 우리가 그것을 조사하지 않았을 것처럼요.
I guess he does think he's smarter than others.
내 생각엔 그 사람이 다른 사람들보다 더 똑똑하다고 생각하는 것 같아 .
He tripped over his own feet.
그는 자신의 발에 걸려 넘어졌습니다.
Let's go inside.
안에 들어 가자.
You haven't figured out anything.
당신은 아무것도 알아내지 못했습니다.
Why don't you undo this before we start talking?
얘기를 시작하기 전에 이 작업을 취소하는 게 어때요 ?
The fingers that punched in
찔러넣은 손가락들
the PIN at the ATM to withdraw money.
돈을 인출하려면 ATM에서 PIN을 입력하세요.
It's similar
비슷해요
to Woo Ho-sung's hand.
우호성의 손에.
Did you see it?
당신은 그것을 볼 않았다?
When I went to the massage parlor and when I cuffed him.
안마시술소에 갔을 때 와 수갑을 채웠을 때
I saw his hands.
나는 그의 손을 보았다.
Woo Ho-sung is also conscious of that.
우호성 역시 그것을 의식하고 있다.
It looks like it.
그럴 것 같습니다.
Are other detectives watching me
다른 형사들이 나를 보고 있는 걸까요?
from behind that wall?
저 벽 뒤에서?
You know why you're here, right?
당신이 여기 왜 왔는지 아시죠?
How many of you are there?
여러분은 몇 명이나 있나요?
Didn't you hear me? I asked you a question.
내 말 못 들었어? 내가 당신에게 질문을했습니다.
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
She told you when she cuffed you.
그녀가 당신에게 수갑을 채웠을 때 말했어요.
Abduction.
외 전.
Who? Who did I abduct?
WHO? 내가 누구를 납치했나요?
You would know better than us.
당신은 우리보다 더 잘 알 것입니다.
Do you have evidence?
증거가 있나요?
That's why we arrested you.
그래서 우리가 당신을 체포했어요.
Even if you search through my house,
우리 집을 뒤져봐도
you won't find anything.
당신은 아무것도 찾을 수 없습니다.
SCIENTIFIC INVESTIGATIONS
과학적 조사
Did you find anything?
뭔가 찾았나요?
I don't see anything in particular.
특별히 아무것도 보이지 않습니다.
He formatted everything.
그는 모든 것을 포맷했습니다.
This is you, isn't it?
바로 당신이죠, 그렇죠?
CCTV FOOTAGE EVIDENCE
CCTV 영상 증거
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
You used the debit card of a woman who went missing and withdrew cash.
실종 여성의 직불카드를 이용해 현금을 인출했습니다.
Show me
보여줘
the evidence that this is me.
이게 나라는 증거.
Where is that woman?
그 여자는 어디에 있나요?
Who?
WHO?
This is you.
이것은 당신입니다.
Where is she?
그녀는 어디 있습니까?
I really have no idea what you're talking about.
무슨 말을 하는지 전혀 모르겠어요 .
At 2 p.m. on February 24,
2월 24일 오후 2시,
tell me where you were.
당신이 어디에 있었는지 말해주세요.
I slept at home.
나는 집에서 잤다.
Not that. Give me something else.
하지 그. 다른 것을 주세요.
Something more feasible.
더 실현 가능한 것.
I said I slept at home.
나는 집에서 잤다고 말했다.
Do you expect me to believe that you were asleep in broad daylight?
당신이 대낮에 자고 있었다고 내가 믿을 것이라고 생각하시나요 ?
In this situation?
이러한 상황에서?
What would I do on weekends? I should sleep.
주말에는 무엇을 할까요? 자야겠다.
You said you had a girlfriend.
여자친구가 있다고 하더군요.
If anything, you would've gone out on a date.
그랬다면 데이트하러 나갔을 거예요.
We went out the day before.
우리는 전날 나갔습니다.
I need a day to rest.
쉬는 날이 필요해요.
It was my day off too.
나도 쉬는 날이었는데.
You don't know who I am, do you?
당신은 내가 누군지 모르죠?
This is you. I know it is.
이것은 당신입니다. 나는 그것이다는 것을 안다.
Do you have evidence?
증거가 있나요?
If you don't, you have to believe me.
그렇지 않다면 내 말을 믿어야 해요.
The dead karaoke bar employee
죽은 노래방 직원
found on that hill was probably killed by him too, right?
그 언덕에서 발견된 것도 아마 그 사람에 의해 살해되었을 거예요, 그렇죠?
I believe so.
나는 그렇다고 믿는다.
The dead body had traces of rape too.
시체에는 성폭행 흔적도 남아 있었다.
We must get him to confess to the sexual assault too.
그에게도 성폭행 사실을 자백하도록 해야 합니다 .
How did he seem? Is he a little different now?
그 사람은 어땠나요? 이제 그 사람은 좀 달라졌나요?
He did not show any emotional distress.
그는 어떠한 감정적인 고통도 나타내지 않았습니다.
He seemed rather calm in a startling situation.
그는 놀라운 상황 속에서도 다소 침착해 보였다.
It looks like he has an antisocial personality disorder.
반사회적 인격장애를 앓고 있는 것 같습니다 .
Like a psychopath?
정신병자 같나요?
-Yes. -Someone extremely self-centered,
-예. -지나치게 자기중심적인 사람,
who lacks a sense of sympathy
동정심이 부족한 사람
and a guilty conscience.
그리고 죄책감.
It looked like he kept two dogs.
개 두 마리를 키우는 것 같았어요.
It's probably a cover-up.
아마도 은폐일 겁니다.
I'm sure he only used them to lure the victims.
그는 피해자를 유인하기 위해서만 사용했다고 확신합니다 .
Let's conduct the PCL-R on him later.
나중에 그 사람에 대해 PCL-R을 실시합시다.
He seems to be the type to show aggression selectively.
선택적으로 공격성을 보이는 타입인 것 같아요 .
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
People like him have a high level of self-control.
그와 같은 사람들은 높은 수준의 자제력을 가지고 있습니다.
They keep their composure until the moment
그들은 그 순간까지 평정심을 유지한다
of their crime. They won't show their emotions.
그들의 범죄. 그들은 자신의 감정을 보여주지 않을 것입니다.
But once he begins to attack,
하지만 일단 공격을 시작하면
he becomes more brutal and violent than others.
그는 다른 사람들보다 더 잔인하고 폭력적이 됩니다.
Are you saying he picks and chooses his victims?
피해자를 골라서 선택한다는 겁니까 ?
You're right.
네가 옳아.
Gu Young-chun and Nam Ki-Tae
구영춘, 남기태
expressed their aggression toward many unspecified people.
불특정 다수에 대한 공격성을 표명했습니다 .
But that man
그런데 그 사람
only expresses his aggression toward the victims he chose.
자신이 선택한 피해자에 대해서만 공격성을 표현합니다 .
I think we should be more strategic about our interrogation tactics.
나는 우리가 심문 전술에 대해 좀 더 전략적으로 접근해야 한다고 생각합니다 .
Even if we show him evidence, he won't confess that easily.
증거를 보여줘도 그 사람은 쉽게 자백하지 않을 거예요.
Chief Kook and I will interrogate him.
국과장님과 제가 심문하겠습니다.
Two gentlemen are joining me this time.
이번에는 두 명의 신사가 합류했습니다.
Are you here to have a conversation with me?
나와 대화를 나누기 위해 여기 오셨나요 ?
That's right.
좋아요.
What about the other detectives from earlier?
이전의 다른 형사들은 어떻습니까 ?
You'll be talking to us for a while.
당신은 잠시 동안 우리와 이야기를 나누게 될 것입니다.
I told you to get evidence.
증거를 확보하라고 했어요.
I guess it's not going well.
아무래도 잘 안 되는 것 같아요.
Gosh.
이런.
If you wanted to talk to me,
나랑 얘기하고 싶으면,
you should have at least brought me some water.
적어도 나 에게 물이라도 좀 가져왔어야 했는데.
Is that all you need?
그게 전부인가요?
We're here to talk to you.
우리는 당신과 이야기하기 위해 여기에 있습니다.
But we're not here to bring you water.
하지만 우리는 여러분에게 물을 가져다주러 온 것이 아닙니다.
Let us know once you actually get thirsty.
실제로 목이 마르면 알려주십시오.
I'll get you some water then.
그럼 물 좀 갖다줄게요.
What are they doing?
그들은 무엇을 하고 있나요?
Just let them do their thing. They have their own system.
그냥 그들이 할 일을 하게 놔두세요. 그들은 그들만의 시스템을 가지고 있습니다.
His attitude seems a bit different from before.
그의 태도는 이전과는 조금 달라진 것 같다.
Whose attitude?
누구의 태도인가요?
-Song Ha-young's? -Yes.
-송하영 씨요? -예.
Rightfully so.
당연히 그렇습니다.
After all, he went through a lot.
결국 그는 많은 일을 겪었습니다.
This guy is different.
이 사람은 달라요.
He probably subdued the victims in a matter of seconds
그는 아마도 몇 초 만에 희생자들을 제압했을 것입니다
and clouded their emotional judgment.
감정적 판단을 흐리게 했습니다.
Then he probably continued his act
그러면 아마 계속 연기를 했을 것 같아요
just like he was trying to have a power struggle by making me bring water.
물을 가져오라고 해서 권력다툼을 하려는 것처럼 .
I've been sitting here
난 여기 앉아 있었어
and talking to the detectives since I got here.
여기 온 이후 로 형사들과 이야기를 나누었어요 .
What else do you want to talk about?
또 무슨 이야기를 하고 싶나요?
We have our own set of questions.
우리는 우리 자신의 질문을 가지고 있습니다.
If you have time for this,
이럴 시간이 있다면,
wouldn't it be better spent looking for evidence outside?
밖에서 증거를 찾는 데 쓰는 것이 낫지 않을까요 ?
All you're doing is sitting here…
여기 앉아서만 하고 계시나요???
and running your mouth.
그리고 입을 다물고 있습니다.
We're looking for evidence. So don't worry about it.
우리는 증거를 찾고 있습니다. 그러니 걱정하지 마세요.
All right. If you say so.
괜찮은. 당신이 그렇게 말한다면.
It won't take long to find evidence.
증거를 찾는 데는 오랜 시간이 걸리지 않습니다.
Why is that jerk so brazen?
저 새끼는 왜 이렇게 뻔뻔해?
You know denying their charges shamelessly is their specialty.
뻔뻔하게 혐의를 부인하는 게 그들의 특기인 거 아시죠 ?
According to Chief Kook,
국과장에 따르면,
his self-control is very high.
그의 자제력은 매우 높다.
And it looks like he's trying to control his emotions even now.
그리고 지금도 감정을 조절하려고 노력하는 것 같아요 .
He asked for water as soon as he saw them
보자마자 물을 달라고 하더군요.
to test whether or not he could control them.
그가 그들을 통제할 수 있는지 테스트하기 위해 .
Does he think he can intimidate them?
그는 자신이 그들을 위협할 수 있다고 생각하는가?
How dare he?
그가 어떻게 감히?
Let me ask you a few questions.
몇 가지 질문을 드리겠습니다.
Your wife and mother-in-law died
당신의 아내와 시어머니가 돌아가셨습니다.
in a fire a few years ago.
몇 년 전에 화재가 났어요.
And you only took your son when you escaped.
그리고 당신은 탈출할 때 아들만 데리고 갔죠 .
When you think about it again, how do you feel?
다시 생각해 보면 어떤 느낌이 드시나요?
Why must I think about that now?
왜 내가 지금 그것에 대해 생각해야 합니까?
I'm just asking how you feel or what you're thinking right now.
그냥 지금 기분이 어떤지, 무슨 생각을 하는지 물어보는 거예요 .
I don't know
모르겠습니다
how the fire has anything to do with this incident.
화재가 이번 사건과 어떤 관련이 있는지.
Why are you bringing up my son?
왜 내 아들을 키우는 거죠?
Your son?
당신의 아들?
I wonder how your son would feel once he finds out that his dad is
아들이 자기 아빠가 그런 사람이라는 사실을 알게 되면 어떤 기분이 들지 궁금하네요.
a serial murderer and rapist.
연쇄 살인범이자 강간범.
You see,
알다시피,
he's too young to know anything.
그는 너무 어려서 아무것도 모른다.
Not yet.
아직 아님.
No. Listen.
아뇨. 들어보세요.
Nothing has been proven yet.
아직 입증된 것은 없습니다.
I really don't follow you.
난 정말 당신을 따르지 않습니다.
That's right.
좋아요.
"Not yet."
"아직 아님."
You received a hefty sum of money
당신은 엄청난 돈을 받았습니다.
from the insurance claim.
보험 청구부터.
Are you
당신은
suspecting me right now?
지금 나를 의심하는 거야?
You see, the fire…
보이시나요, 불???
started because of the mosquito incense stick.
모기 향 때문에 시작됐어요 .
And the detectives who investigated the case…
그리고 사건을 조사한 형사들은 ???
couldn't prove anything.
아무것도 증명할 수 없었습니다.
"Couldn't" prove anything?
"할 수 없었다"는 것은 아무것도 증명할 수 없습니까?
Right.
오른쪽.
They couldn't prove anything.
그들은 아무것도 증명할 수 없었습니다.
Because there was nothing to prove. Isn't that obvious?
증명할 것이 없었기 때문이다. 당연하지 않나요?
I was trying to survive the fire with my son.
나는 아들과 함께 화재에서 살아남으려고 노력하고 있었습니다.
All we did was escape. That's all.
우리가 한 일은 탈출뿐이었습니다. 그게 다야.
I mean…
내 말은???
we didn't say otherwise, did we?
우리는 달리 말하지 않았죠?
Why did you send your son to your cousin's house?
왜 아들을 사촌집에 보냈나요 ?
Once I go to work,
일단 회사에 가보면
there's no one to look after him.
그를 돌봐줄 사람이 아무도 없어요.
How old is your son? Is he 11 years old?
당신의 아들은 몇 살입니까? 11살이에요?
Why are you curious about that?
왜 그게 궁금해?
I was just wondering if you know your son's age.
나는 단지 당신이 당신 아들의 나이를 알고 있는지 궁금합니다 .
Don't be absurd.
터무니없는 소리하지 마십시오.
Don't be rude.
무례하게 굴지 마세요.
Do you want your son to find out
아들이 알기를 바라나요?
that his father is a serial murderer and rapist?
그 사람 아버지 가 연쇄살인범이자 강간범이라고요?
That jerk.
그 멍청이.
Why are you doing this to me?
나한테 왜 이러는 걸까요?
I'm sure you know why.
그 이유를 아시리라 믿습니다.
Let's stop talking about my son.
내 아들 얘기는 그만하자.
Why? You don't like it? Is it uncomfortable?
왜? 당신은 그것을 좋아하지 않습니까? 불편합니까?
It has nothing to do with this case.
이 사건과는 아무 관련이 없습니다.
You said you didn't do it.
당신은 그것을하지 않았다고 말했다.
But you're still ashamed when you think about your son?
그런데 아직도 아들 생각하면 부끄럽나요 ?
I'm curious too.
나도 궁금하다.
Why is he bringing up his son?
그 사람은 왜 아들을 키우는 걸까요?
Woo Ho-sung's narcissism.
우호성의 나르시시즘.
HAVING ATTACHMENT TO ONESELF
자기 자신에 대한 집착
Serial murderers and rapists who commit crimes for pleasure
쾌락을 위해 범죄를 저지르는 연쇄 살인범, 강간범
like Woo Ho-sung will show a high level of narcissism.
우호성처럼 높은 나르시시즘을 보여줄 것이다.
He did seem to be full of himself.
그는 정말 자기 자신으로 가득 차 있는 것 같았습니다.
People tend to develop excessive self-attachment
사람들은 과도한 자기애착을 발달시키는 경향이 있습니다.
as a defense mechanism against pain and despair.
고통과 절망에 대한 방어기제이다 .
And when they experience an attachment injury,
그리고 애착 손상을 겪게 되면 ,
they feel a sense of humiliation and hopelessness.
그들은 굴욕감과 절망감을 느낍니다 .
So the attachment toward others gets directed to themselves.
그래서 다른 사람에 대한 애착은 자신에게로 향하게 됩니다.
A sense of humiliation and hopelessness?
굴욕감과 절망감?
That can cause narcissism?
그것이 나르시시즘을 유발할 수 있나요?
They must deny their reality that they can't be loved.
그들은 사랑받을 수 없다는 현실을 부정해야 한다 .
How can we get Woo Ho-sung to talk?
우호성을 어떻게 말하게 할 수 있을까요?
We need to find out the target of his unconditional attachment.
그의 무조건적인 애착의 대상을 찾아내야 한다 .
Unconditional attachment?
무조건 애착?
It has to be his family, right?
그 사람 가족이겠죠?
-His parents or kids. -It can't be his parents.
-그의 부모님이나 아이들. -그 사람 부모님일 리가 없어요.
Having a big trauma like an attachment injury
애착 손상 등 큰 외상을 입은 경우
must mean that he didn't feel loved by his parents.
그가 부모로부터 사랑을 받지 못했다는 뜻일 겁니다 .
Then it has to be his kids.
그렇다면 그의 아이들이어야합니다.
Does he have kids?
그에게 아이가 있나요?
He has a son in elementary school.
그에게는 초등학교에 다니는 아들이 있다.
His cousin is looking after him.
그의 사촌이 그를 돌보고 있다.
Fine. If not your son, how about your parents?
괜찮은. 당신의 아들이 아니라면, 당신의 부모님은 어떻습니까?
Why do you keep…
왜 계속???
trying to talk about
에 대해 이야기하려고
my personal life?
내 사생활?
That's why we're here.
그것이 우리가 여기 있는 이유입니다.
We analyze criminal behavior.
범죄 행위를 분석합니다.
CHIEF KOOK YOUNG-SOO
국영수 실장
You haven't proven…
증명하지 않았나요???
anything yet.
아직 아무것도.
I really don't understand…
정말 이해가 안가나요???
what you're talking about.
당신이 말하는 것.
-How was your relationship with your dad? -My dad?
-아버지와의 관계는 어땠나요? - 우리 아빠?
-He was strict. -Did he hit you too?
-그는 엄격했어요. - 그 사람이 당신도 때렸어요?
No.
아니요.
He never hit me.
그는 나를 때린 적이 없습니다.
Was your family well-off?
당신의 가족은 잘 지내셨나요?
Why do you ask?
왜 물어보나요?
Do you think I had a tough upbringing and grew up in poverty?
내가 힘들게 자랐고 가난하게 자랐을 것 같나요?
This is a standard question.
이것은 표준 질문입니다.
Gosh. You guys are unbelievable.
이런. 너희들은 믿을 수 없다.
You guys are biased against people.
너희들은 사람에 대해 편견이 있다.
Enough with these ridiculous questions.
이런 말도 안되는 질문은 이제 그만.
Go out there…
거기로 나가???
and find more evidence.
그리고 더 많은 증거를 찾아보세요.
You just wait.
그냥 기다리세요.
It won't be long.
오래 걸리지 않을 것입니다.
Gosh. That jerk.
이런. 그 멍청이.
How's the search going?
수색은 어떻게 진행되고 있나요?
He has a lot of stuff.
그 사람은 물건이 많아요.
And he especially has a lot of clothes.
그리고 특히 옷이 많아요.
That's not an excuse. We have to bring everything in.
그건 변명이 아닙니다. 모든 것을 가져와야 합니다.
Whenever we tried to provoke him,
우리가 그를 자극하려고 할 때마다
he kept asking us if we found any evidence.
그는 우리에게 증거가 있는지 계속 물었습니다.
He thinks he got rid of all the evidence.
그는 모든 증거를 제거했다고 생각합니다.
What about his call history?
그의 통화 기록은 어떻습니까?
We used his call history since February
우리는 2월부터 그의 통화 기록을 사용했습니다
and tracked his whereabouts with his cell phone
그리고 휴대폰으로 그의 행방을 추적했다.
to check the security footage as we speak.
우리가 말하는 동안 보안 영상을 확인하려고요.
Gosh. It will take forever.
이런. 영원히 걸릴 것입니다.
No news from the NFS, right?
NFS에서는 소식이 없지요?
There's too much stuff from his house.
그 사람 집에 물건이 너무 많아요.
So it will take a long time just to run the DNA tests on them.
그래서 그들에 대한 DNA 테스트를 실행하는 데만 오랜 시간이 걸릴 것입니다 .
He set his car on fire for a reason.
그는 어떤 이유로 차에 불을 질렀습니다.
He formatted his computer too.
그 사람 컴퓨터도 포맷했어요.
Gosh. We just need some hard evidence to make the arrest.
이런. 체포하려면 확실한 증거가 필요해요 .
He seemed experienced in starting a fire.
그는 불을 지른 경험이 있는 것 같았다.
Serial killers often commit arson too.
연쇄 살인범도 방화를 저지르는 경우가 많습니다.
Every single one of them started a fire.
그들 모두는 불을 지폈습니다.
We'll have to check a few more things, but I'm sure he's the culprit.
몇 가지 더 확인해봐야겠지만 범인은 확실해요.
He said the police "couldn't" prove anything.
그는 경찰이 아무것도 증명할 수 없다고 말했습니다.
Wait. His response is wrong.
기다리다. 그의 반응은 틀렸다.
He shouldn't say the police couldn't prove it.
경찰이 그것을 증명할 수 없다고 말해서는 안 됩니다 .
He should be arguing that he was innocent.
그는 자신이 결백하다고 주장해야 한다.
He killed his wife and mother-in-law? No human can do this.
그가 아내와 시어머니를 죽였다고? 인간은 이것을 할 수 없습니다.
Listen. Are you telling me the only thing we can do right now is
듣다. 지금 우리가 할 수 있는 유일한 일은 나에게 말하는 거야 ?
sit around this table and wait for a call from the NFS?
이 테이블에 둘러앉아 NFS의 전화를 기다리시겠습니까?
We have 32 hours left.
이제 32시간 남았습니다.
You can eat now.
이제 먹어도 됩니다.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
You should've asked me first.
나한테 먼저 물어봤어야지.
I don't eat jjajangmyeon.
저는 짜장면을 안 먹어요.
It's bad for your health.
건강에 좋지 않습니다.
-What? -I want a proper meal.
-무엇? - 제대로 된 식사를 하고 싶다.
With soybean paste soup.
된장국으로.
Or with cheonggukjang stew.
아니면 청국장 찌개를 곁들여 보세요.
What? It's bad for your health? He's unbelievable.
무엇? 건강에 안 좋은가요? 그는 믿을 수가 없어요.
Why are these scumbags all so health-conscious?
이 쓰레기들은 왜 모두 건강에 관심이 있습니까?
Who else was like that other than Nam Ki-Tae?
남기태 말고 또 그런 사람이 있었나 ?
Gu Young-chun.
구영춘.
Those scumbags can live long lives in prison.
그 쓰레기들은 감옥에서 오래 살 수 있습니다.
I'll go feed Woo Ho-sung.
우호성 밥 먹으러 갈게.
-Okay. -See you in a bit.
-좋아요. - 조금 있다 뵙겠습니다.
-See you.
-또 봐요.
Let's resume the interview with him after he's done eating.
식사를 마친 후 인터뷰를 재개하겠습니다 .
-Okay. -Sounds good.
-좋아요. - 좋은 것 같아요.
While we're eating, let's think about his MO from his perspective.
밥을 먹으면서 그의 관점에서 그의 MO를 생각해 보자.
-From Woo Ho-sung's perspective? -Yes.
-우호성 입장에서는? -예.
He used his expensive car to lure his victims.
그는 피해자를 유인하기 위해 값비싼 차를 이용했습니다 .
The victims got into his car without suspecting anything.
피해자들은 아무것도 의심하지 않고 그의 차에 탑승했습니다.
For that to happen,
그러려면
there are various conditions that had to be met.
충족해야 할 다양한 조건이 있습니다 .
He must've cared a lot about what he wore.
그는 자신이 입는 옷에 많은 신경을 썼을 것입니다.
Yes, they found a ton of clothes at his house.
예, 그의 집에서 엄청난 양의 옷을 발견했습니다 .
Clothes that look expensive.
비싸 보이는 옷
Winter clothes that he must've worn often.
자주 입었을 겨울옷.
We should check those first. It'll be faster.
우리는 그것들을 먼저 확인해야 합니다. 더 빨라질 거예요.
He lured his victims inside his vehicle,
그는 피해자를 자신의 차량 안으로 유인했고,
so maybe not thick winter jackets.
그래서 두꺼운 겨울 재킷은 아닐 수도 있어요.
He most likely wore expensive-looking clothes.
그는 아마도 비싸 보이는 옷을 입었을 것입니다.
Let's check neutral-colored shirts and jackets first.
먼저 뉴트럴 컬러의 셔츠와 재킷부터 살펴보자 .
Why does the color matter?
색상이 왜 중요합니까?
Strangers wearing neutral colors tend to seem more trustworthy
무채색 옷을 입은 낯선 사람이 더 신뢰스러워 보이는 경향이 있습니다.
than those in loud colors.
화려한 색상보다
That's right. This way, we can save time.
좋아요. 이렇게 하면 시간을 절약할 수 있습니다.
Start with clothes that he probably wore often.
그가 자주 입었던 옷부터 시작해보세요 .
Neutral-colored winter shirts and jackets that look expensive.
비싸보이는 뉴트럴 컬러의 겨울 셔츠와 재킷 .
We ordered you what you wanted to eat,
우리는 먹고 싶은 것을 주문했는데,
so it's now your turn to give us the answer we want.
이제 우리가 원하는 답변을 제공할 차례입니다 .
You little punk, you're really something.
이 꼬마야, 넌 정말 대단해.
I'm getting sleepy now that I've eaten.
밥을 먹으니까 이제 졸려요.
All right, let's get this done fast.
알았어, 빨리 끝내자.
That's exactly what we're trying to do now.
그것이 바로 우리가 지금 하려고 하는 일입니다.
You punk.
이 새끼야.
Are you here for fun?
재미로 여기 오셨나요?
Look, Detective.
보세요, 형사님.
You arrested me without a warrant based on mere suspicion. Am I wrong?
당신은 단지 의심만으로 영장도 없이 나를 체포했습니다 . 내가 잘못?
-What? -And you're treating me like dirt.
-무엇? -그리고 당신은 나를 흙처럼 대하고 있어요.
What if I'm not the culprit?
내가 범인이 아니라면?
What if
만약
I sue you?
내가 당신을 고소한다고요?
What will you do then?
그러면 당신은 무엇을 할 것인가?
You little punk, you have a knack
이 꼬마 새끼야, 너에겐 재주가 있구나
for getting people riled up.
사람들을 화나게 만들기 위해서요.
Chief Park.
박 과장.
-Let go. You piece of… -Chief Park, please.
- 놔. 당신은 ??? - 박 과장님 부탁해요.
You'd better confess
차라리 고백을 해라
when you still have the chance to or you'll regret it later, you punk.
아직 기회가 있거나 나중에 후회할 때, 이 새끼야.
I'm scared.
나 무서워.
Darn it.
젠장.
That scumbag is so confident.
그 쓰레기는 너무 자신감이 넘쳤어요.
What did the NFS say?
NFS는 뭐라고 말했습니까?
I asked them to check his winter clothes first.
나는 먼저 그의 겨울옷을 확인해 보라고 했다.
Darn it.
젠장.
If we find the victims' DNA, it's a done deal.
피해자의 DNA를 찾으면 거래가 완료된 것입니다.
Let's wait and see.
기다리고 보자.
People like him open up easily to those
그와 같은 사람들은 그런 사람들에게 쉽게 마음을 연다.
who are either younger than them or have low-level positions.
자신보다 어리거나 직위가 낮은 사람.
It's one of the common traits of a narcissist.
그것은 나르시시스트의 일반적인 특성 중 하나입니다.
Correct.
옳은.
They want to feel supported and acknowledged.
그들은 지지 와 인정을 받고 싶어합니다 .
We shouldn't make him feel inferior.
우리는 그 사람이 열등감을 느끼게 해서는 안 됩니다.
Then should Detective Nam deal with him without Chief Park?
그렇다면 남형사는 박 서장 없이 그를 처리해야 할까?
Let's wait and see.
기다리고 보자.
You killed this woman.
당신이 이 여자를 죽였습니다.
Take your time and have a look.
시간을 내어 한번 살펴보세요.
Can I get a cup of coffee?
커피 한잔 드릴까요?
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
Looks like he'll confess, right?
고백할 것 같죠?
Either that or he just felt a pang of guilt.
아니면 그냥 죄책감을 느꼈던 것일 수도 있다.
He did show a reaction at that moment,
그 순간 그는 반응을 보였습니다.
but we'll have to wait and see what he does.
하지만 우리는 그가 무엇을 하는지 기다려야 할 것입니다 .
He's been denying everything this whole time.
그는 그동안 모든 것을 부인해왔습니다.
He won't be swayed that easily only by the victims' photos.
피해자 사진만으로는 그렇게 쉽게 흔들리지 않을 것이다 .
But he's human after all.
하지만 그는 결국 인간이다.
Based on his attitude so far, I know he won't confess easily.
지금까지의 태도로 볼 때, 그가 쉽게 고백하지 않을 것이라는 것을 알고 있습니다.
And he managed to be cleared of the insurance scam charges.
그리고 그는 가까스로 보험사기 혐의를 면하게 됐다 .
These women aren't even recognizable.
이 여자들은 알아보지도 못합니다.
What do you want me to do with these photos?
내가 이 사진들로 무엇을 하길 바라나요?
That scumbag is clearly a psychopath.
저 쓰레기는 분명 사이코패스입니다.
Why did he put the cup on top of the photo?
왜 사진 위에 컵을 올려놓은 걸까요 ?
Of course, he wasn't going to confess.
물론 그는 자백을 하지는 않았다.
"These women aren't even recognizable."
"이 여자들은 알아보지도 못해요."
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
They're photos of one victim.
한 피해자의 사진이에요.
It's not the owner of the debit card he used to withdraw money.
그가 돈을 인출하는 데 사용한 직불카드의 소유자는 아닙니다 .
It's the karaoke bar employee
노래방 직원이에요
who was found dead in the woods.
숲 속에서 숨진 채 발견된 사람.
He should be under the impression
그 사람은 인상을 받아야 해
that it's the victim we're accusing him of killing.
우리가 그를 살해했다고 비난하는 사람이 바로 피해자라는 것입니다 .
But he assumed that
하지만 그는 그렇게 생각했다
it'd be more than one person.
한 사람 이상이 될 것입니다.
What? Then…
무엇? 그 다음에???
It means there is more than one victim.
피해자가 한 명 이상이라는 뜻이다.
He's the culprit.
그 사람이 범인이에요.
He killed several women.
그는 여러 명의 여성을 죽였습니다.
Hence the reaction.
따라서 반응.
If he didn't do it,
만약 그가 그렇게 하지 않았다면,
he'd know nothing about the victim or the location.
그는 피해자 나 위치에 대해 아무것도 몰랐습니다.
So the fact that he said he couldn't recognize them…
그럼 그 사람 이 그들을 알아볼 수 없다고 말한 사실은 ???
is certainly odd.
확실히 이상해요.
I found something.
뭔가를 찾았어요.
What did you eat?
무엇을 먹었나요?
Pizza.
피자.
Here it is.
여기있어.
DNA INFORMATION LAB
DNA 정보 연구실
-Good morning. -Did you work all night?
-좋은 아침이에요. - 밤새도록 일하셨나요?
-Look. -What?
-바라보다. -무엇?
NFS HAN BONG-AM
NFS 한봉암
The NFS?
NFS?
Goodness, they pulled an all-nighter too.
맙소사, 그들도 밤새도록 잤어요.
Hey.
여기요.
Yes, okay.
그래 괜찮아.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
They found a bloodstain on Woo Ho-sung's jacket.
우호성의 재킷에서 혈흔이 발견됐다 .
The DNA matches that of the body found in the woods.
DNA는 숲에서 발견된 시체의 DNA와 일치합니다.
Finally, thank goodness.
마지막으로, 맙소사.
You're dead meat now, you punk.
넌 이제 죽은 고기야, 이 새끼야.
Also, they found a half-burnt lipstick
그리고 반쯤 탄 립스틱도 발견했어요
in the burnt vehicle.
불탄 차량에서.
-Did they manage to lift DNA? -Not yet.
- DNA를 들어올리는 데 성공했나요? -아직 아님.
I just wanted to keep you informed.
나는 단지 당신에게 정보를 제공하고 싶었습니다.
I'll go in and let them know.
내가 들어가서 그들에게 알려줄게.
They've faxed the report.
그 사람들이 보고서를 팩스로 보냈어요.
-Okay. -Good work, everyone.
-좋아요. -모두들 수고했어요.
What would we have done without you guys?
너희들이 없었다면 우리는 어떻게 됐을까?
What is it, Ha-young?
뭐야, 하영아?
The lipstick.
립스틱.
Maybe it belongs to a victim we don't know about yet.
어쩌면 우리가 아직 모르는 피해자의 것일 수도 있습니다 .
We need to get a confession out of him.
그에게서 자백을 받아야 해요.
Goodness.
선량.
We found something.
뭔가를 찾았어요.
This is what we've been eagerly waiting for.
이것이 우리가 간절히 기다려온 것입니다.
DNA ANALYSIS REPORT
DNA 분석 보고서
The evidence.
그 증거.
It's the victim's DNA…
피해자의 DNA인가요???
that we found from your clothes.
우리가 네 옷에서 찾은 거야.
We found it.
우리는 그것을 찾았습니다.
BELONGS TO THE SAME PERSON
같은 사람에게 속함
HEO GEUM-YOUNG
허금영
WORKS AT YEONJIN CHINESE RESTAURANT
연진중식당에서 근무
HEO GEUM-YOUNG, 51
허금영, 51세
SPECIMEN 1 AND 2 BELONG TO THE SAME PERSON
표본 1과 2는 같은 사람의 것입니다
Captain Yoon, the one who just left.
방금 떠난 윤대위.
Ask her to come in.
그녀에게 들어오라고 하세요.
Stop trying to conjure up a trick. Just confess, you scumbag.
속임수를 쓰려고 노력하지 마세요. 그냥 고백해, 이 쓰레기야.
I will confess.
고백하겠습니다.
In return,
답례로,
I want Captain Yoon here.
나는 윤 선장이 여기에 있기를 원한다.
I'll go get a confession out of him.
나는 그에게 고백을 받으러 갈 것이다.
Hold on.
기다리다.
I'll go in first.
나 먼저 들어갈게.
-You? -I want to say something to Woo Ho-sung.
-너? -우호성 씨에게 하고 싶은 말이 있다.
-It'll be quick. -Sure, go ahead.
- 금방 될 거예요. -응 해봐.
-Will you be all right? -Yes.
- 괜찮으시겠어요? -예.
I'll go in myself.
내가 직접 들어갈게.
How do you feel?
기분이 어때요?
About what?
무엇에 대해서?
You have nowhere to run now.
이제 당신은 도망칠 곳이 없습니다.
You're good at finding evidence.
당신은 증거를 찾는 데 능숙합니다.
Science is much smarter than you think.
과학은 당신이 생각하는 것보다 훨씬 똑똑합니다.
So is the quality of our investigation.
조사의 질도 마찬가지입니다.
That perfect crime you want? There's no such thing.
당신이 원하는 완전범죄? 그런 건 없습니다.
Woo Ho-sung.
우호성.
-Be smart about it. -About what?
- 현명하게 대처하세요. -무엇에 대해서요?
Whether or not you want your son to remember you
당신의 아들이 당신을 기억하기를 원하는지 여부
as an unremorseful murderer until the very end.
끝까지 후회 하지 않는 살인자로 .
And this will be the last time we talk.
그리고 이것이 우리가 이야기하는 마지막 시간이 될 것입니다.
I'm not scared.
나는 두렵지 않다.
I'm not saying this to scare you.
겁 주려고 이런 말을 하는 게 아니다.
I'm telling you that nobody will listen to your story anymore.
더 이상 아무도 당신의 이야기를 듣지 않을 것이라고 말씀드립니다 .
I already know that there are multiple victims.
피해자가 여럿인 것으로 알고 있습니다 .
We have the evidence too.
우리에게도 증거가 있습니다.
I thought you weren't here to talk about the case.
나는 당신이 그 사건에 대해 이야기하기 위해 여기 온 것이 아니라고 생각했습니다 .
-I'm not. -Then let's change the subject.
-난 아니다. -그럼 화제를 바꾸겠습니다.
No. I already have you figured out.
아뇨. 이미 알아냈어요.
Which is why I'm no longer curious.
그렇기 때문에 더 이상 궁금하지 않습니다.
Would it be possible…
가능할까요???
for me to talk privately with Captain Yoon?
윤 선장과 개인적으로 이야기를 나누라고요 ?
I'll be fine.
난 괜찮을거야.
Give me your hands.
손을 주세요.
What is it that you want to say?
당신이 말하고 싶은 것이 무엇입니까?
I'm sure…
확실해???
getting a confession out of someone
누군가에게 고백을 받고
is harder than you detectives think, right?
형사님들이 생각하는 것보다 어려운 일이잖아요 ?
It's the same for the confessor too.
그건 고백자도 마찬가지다.
Which is why…
그것 때문에???
I'm torn.
나는 찢어졌다.
Whether the culprit confesses or not
범인의 자백 여부
is his decision to make.
그가 내리는 결정이다.
Then how…
그러면 어떻게???
can I get him to decide?
그 사람이 결정하게 할 수 있을까요?
Just give the nuance that you understand him to an extent.
당신이 그를 어느 정도 이해한다는 뉘앙스를 주세요 .
Woo Ho-sung has strong narcissistic tendencies.
우호성은 자기애 성향이 강한 편이다.
If you form a rapport with him,
그 사람과 인연을 맺으면
it'll bring about a change in his emotions.
그것은 그의 감정에 변화를 가져올 것입니다 .
Don't you think…
그렇게 생각하지 않나요???
the burden will be lifted once you confess?
고백하면 부담이 가벼워지나요 ?
Whose burden?
누구의 부담인가?
Yours.
당신 것.
And mine too.
그리고 나도 마찬가지다.
Do you really think so?
정말 그렇게 생각해?
I'm sure…
확실해???
you had a reason why you asked for me specifically.
당신 이 나에게 구체적으로 요청한 이유가 있었습니다 .
Whatever it is that you have to tell me,
무슨 일이 있어도 나한테 말해야 해.
I'm ready to listen
난 들을 준비가 됐어
to you.
당신에게.
Why did you do it?
왜 그랬나요?
Must there always…
항상 있어야 하나요???
be a reason
이유가 되다
why you kill someone?
왜 사람을 죽여?
So…
그래서???
you didn't have a reason?
이유가 없었어?
Well, if I had to come up with one,
글쎄요, 제가 하나를 생각해내야 한다면,
it's because I wanted to kill them.
내가 그들을 죽이고 싶었기 때문이다.
How many…
얼마나???
did you murder?
당신이 살인했어요?
We found…
우리는 발견???
components of another victim's lipstick
다른 피해자의 립스틱 성분
from your car.
당신의 차에서.
It will all be revealed in the end.
결국에는 다 밝혀질 것입니다.
That hand.
그 손.
You tried your best to hide your face.
당신은 얼굴을 숨기려고 최선을 다했습니다.
But unfortunately,
하지만 불행하게도,
you weren't able to hide your hand.
당신은 손을 숨길 수 없었습니다.
You've been self-conscious about it all along, right?
당신은 줄곧 그것에 대해 자의식을 갖고 있었죠 , 그렇죠?
Once you are ready to talk to me,
나와 대화할 준비가 되면
I'll come back.
나는 돌아올 것이다.
All right.
괜찮은.
I will talk.
나는 말할 것이다.
The suspect confessed that he murdered all the women
피의자는 여성을 모두 살해했다고 자백했다.
who started going missing in 2006 around Gyeonggi's southwestern area.
2006년부터 경기 남서부 지역에서 실종되기 시작했습니다 .
Early this morning in Suwon, the police found the body of the missing housewife.
오늘 아침 수원에서 경찰이 실종된 주부의 시신을 발견했습니다.
They are continuing their search for the other women's bodies…
그들은 계속해서 다른 여성의 시신을 찾고 있다???
Is this hair?
이게 머리카락인가요?
Oh, I found it!
아, 찾았어요!
-What? -I found something.
-무엇? -뭔가를 찾았어요.
Look.
바라보다.
On the day I planned to murder,
살인을 계획했던 날
I made sure that I executed it.
실행에 옮겼는지 확인했습니다.
No matter what.
무슨 일이 있어도.
You're saying you planned for all seven murders?
일곱 건의 살인을 모두 계획했다는 겁니까 ?
Of course.
물론.
I'm determined from the moment
난 그 순간부터 결심했어
I leave the house.
나는 집을 떠난다.
Did you ever fail?
실패한 적 있나요?
Fail?
실패하다?
I have never failed.
나는 결코 실패한 적이 없습니다.
You see,
알다시피,
it's like a promise I make to myself.
그것은 나 자신과의 약속과 같습니다.
I executed it.
나는 그것을 실행했다.
One way or another.
어떤 식 으로든.
The police intensely investigated the suspect to find out
경찰은 진상 규명을 위해 피의자를 집중 조사했다
if he committed additional crimes until early this morning.
오늘 이른 아침까지 추가 범죄를 저질렀다면
They will also carry out a crime scene reenactment this morning.
오늘 아침에는 범죄 현장 재연 도 진행됩니다 .
Look over here.
여기 좀 보세요.
He reenacted three out of his seven crimes yesterday.
그는 어제 7가지 범죄 중 3가지를 재연했습니다.
The bereaved families and residents were enraged once again
유가족과 주민들은 다시 한 번 분노했다
as they watched him reenact the crime nonchalantly.
그들이 태연하게 범죄를 재현하는 모습을 지켜보는 가운데
I have always known…
나는 항상 알고 있었어???
that I was a psychopath.
내가 사이코패스였다는 걸요.
Why did you think that?
왜 그렇게 생각했어요?
I was watching TV one day.
어느 날 TV를 보고 있었어요.
When I heard
내가 들었을 때
the characteristics of a psychopath…
사이코패스의 특징???
I realized.
나는 깨달았다.
That's me in a nutshell.
간단히 말해서 그게 바로 나다.
Take his hat off. Let me see him!
모자를 벗으세요. 그를 보자!
-My gosh. -That scumbag…
-이럴수가. - 그 쓰레기???
His second crime was by Highway 39, which was his secret burial site.
그의 두 번째 범죄는 그의 비밀 매장지였던 39번 고속도로에서 발생했습니다.
When the police told him to reenact how he dug the ground,
경찰이 땅파는 모습을 재현하라고 했을 때
he was comfortable enough to revise the order.
그는 순서를 수정할 만큼 편안했습니다 .
Saying that he dug the ground after he took the body out of the car.
시신을 차에서 꺼낸 뒤 땅을 팠다고 합니다 .
His calm demeanor as he reenacted the horrible crime
끔찍한 범죄를 재현하는 그의 차분한 태도
made the onlookers even more furious.
관객들을 더욱 분노하게 만들었습니다.
The bereaved families who came later to watch the reenactment
나중에 재연을 관람하러 온 유가족들
were crying out, demanding to see his face.
그의 얼굴을 보라고 소리 치며 울부짖었습니다 .
When do you feel the urge to kill?
언제 죽이고 싶은 충동을 느끼나요?
That is…
그건???
a little difficult to describe
설명하기가 조금 어렵다
with words.
말로.
Hitting on women is a piece of cake.
여성을 때리는 것은 케이크 조각입니다.
You see, those girls…
알겠나, 그 여자들???
They all liked me.
그들은 모두 나를 좋아했습니다.
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
I think it's just you.
나는 그것이 단지 당신이라고 생각합니다.
Why won't you believe me? It's true.
왜 나를 믿지 않습니까? 사실이에요.
They all really liked me.
그들은 모두 나를 정말 좋아했습니다.
I also think…
내 생각에도???
you only look like a petty loser.
당신은 단지 사소한 패배자처럼 보일 뿐입니다.
Sorry for the bad news.
나쁜 소식을 전해드려 죄송합니다.
We…
우리???
do not…
하지 마라???
believe your words.
당신의 말을 믿으십시오.
If they don't listen to me,
그들이 내 말을 듣지 않는다면,
then…
그 다음에???
I take off
나는 이륙한다
my necktie and bind their hands and feet.
내 넥타이를 매고 그들의 손과 발을 묶는다.
The investigation headquarters of the Gyeonggi Agency stated
경기청 수사본부는 다음과 같이 밝혔다
they received the confession from Woo,
우로부터 고백을 받았고,
the suspect who killed the female university student
여대생 살해 용의자
who went missing in February, that he killed seven and buried them
2월에 실종되어 7명을 살해하고 묻었다
until early this year.
올해 초까지
Last month,
지난달
he conducted two psychopathy tests
그는 두 가지 정신병 테스트를 실시했습니다
and was confirmed as a typical psychopath with scores of 27 and 28 respectively.
각각 27점과 28점으로 전형적인 사이코패스로 확인되었습니다 .
I will be
나는 될 것이다
sentenced to death, right?
사형을 선고받았죠?
You should be.
당신은해야한다.
Even after I go up there, I won't find
올라가도 못찾겠어
my peace.
내 평화.
Did you dream of ending up in heaven?
천국에 가는 꿈을 꾸셨나요?
Goodness, Ji-sook.
맙소사, 지숙.
Ji-sook, you've returned in such vain.
지숙아, 너 헛되이 돌아왔구나.
Let's go.
갑시다.
GYEONGGI INVESTIGATION HEADQUARTERS OF SERIAL MISSING WOMEN CASE
경기연쇄 실종여성사건수사 본부
Gil-pyo.
길표.
A souvenir.
기억하기 위해.
Park Dae-woong! Big bear! You did it!
박대웅! 큰 곰! 훌륭해!
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Good work, everyone.
모두들 수고했어요.
-Great job. -Great work.
-잘 했어. -훌륭한 일.
It's sad to see you go.
가신다니 안타깝습니다.
You don't look too sad.
별로 슬퍼 보이지는 않네요.
Tell me about it.
그것에 대해 말해주십시오.
Well, I may not look sad,
뭐, 슬픈 표정은 아닐지도 모르지만,
but I'm glad and sad to see you go.
하지만 당신이 가는 걸 보니 기쁘기도 하고 슬프기도 해요.
We'll visit.
우리는 방문할 것이다.
It only takes us 50 minutes to get here from Seoul Agency…
서울대리점에서 여기까지 50분밖에 안걸리나요 ???
I don't expect you to come.
나는 당신이 올 것이라고 기대하지 않습니다.
You're one to talk. I don't expect you to come either.
당신은 말할 사람입니다. 나는 당신도 올 것이라고 기대하지 않습니다.
If we have to meet again, it'll have to be another case…
다시 만나야 한다면 또 다른 사건이겠죠???
Goodness, no.
맙소사, 아니.
In that case, I'd rather not meet at all.
그렇다면 차라리 아예 만나지 않는 게 낫겠다.
Let's just keep our memories deep inside, right here.
우리의 추억을 여기 깊은 곳에 간직하자 .
Captain Yoon, you should also share something.
윤 대위 님도 공유 좀 해주세요.
Let's go now.
이제 가자.
-Great work. -Great job.
-훌륭한 일. -잘 했어.
-Chief Park, let's have some soju. -Let's do that.
-박과장, 소주 한잔 하자. -그걸하자.
Stay healthy, okay?
건강하게 지내세요, 알았죠?
Yes, be mindful of your health too.
네, 건강에도 유의하세요.
-Bye. -Goodbye.
-안녕. -안녕히 가세요.
-Let's go. -Great job.
-갑시다. -잘 했어.
Why are you moving on a day when I'm free?
내가 한가한 날 왜 이사가는 거야?
Because I moved to the neighborhood you told me to.
네가 말한 동네로 이사 왔으니까 .
I can't move here because there are lots of robberies.
강도가 많아서 여기로 이사할 수 없어요 .
Another place is too dangerous because of burglars.
또 다른 곳은 강도 때문에 너무 위험해요 .
When I see you, I realize knowing too much can hurt.
당신을 보면 너무 많은 것을 아는 것이 상처가 될 수 있다는 것을 깨닫습니다.
Thanks to me, you came to a safe neighborhood.
덕분에 안전한 동네로 왔어요.
According to statistics, this area has 50 percent fewer crimes
통계에 따르면 이 지역은 범죄율이 50% 적습니다.
compared to other neighborhoods.
다른 동네에 비해.
And a detective of the Wide-Area Investigation Squad is your neighbor.
그리고 광역 수사대 형사가 당신의 이웃입니다.
So when will Detective Nam get here?
그럼 남 형사는 언제 오나요?
-Detective Nam? -Yes.
-남 형사요? -예.
I have your order of beef intestines.
주문하신 쇠고기 내장이 있습니다.
-These are all mine? -Yes.
-이거 다 내꺼야? -예.
My gosh, this is a lot. All right.
맙소사, 이거 너무 많아. 괜찮은.
-Goodbye. -Thank you.
-안녕히 가세요. -감사합니다.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
When did you get all these?
언제 이것들을 다 얻었나요?
-I had to run. -That looks good.
-달려야 했어요. -좋아 보인다.
Detective Nam got these?
남 형사가 이걸 가지고 있어요?
You can get beef intestines to go?
쇠고기 내장을 갈 수 있습니까?
Yes, you can get just about anything to go now.
예, 이제 무엇이든 얻을 수 있습니다 .
It's much more convenient since it's already cooked.
이미 조리되어 있어서 훨씬 편해요 .
It's really good.
이거 정말 좋다.
-Is it? -Yes, try some.
-그렇나요? - 응, 좀 먹어봐.
Let's make a toast first.
먼저 건배를 합시다.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
This is how I recharge the energy I lost from moving.
움직이면서 잃어버린 에너지를 재충전하는 방법입니다 .
The mood here is perfect.
여기 분위기는 완벽해요.
Let's get together from time to time
가끔 같이 모이자
and have meetings here.
그리고 여기서 회의를 해요.
-It'd be nice. -Sounds great.
-좋겠네요. -좋네요.
I got it.
알겠어요.
Isn't this the first time we got together outside of work?
우리가 회사 밖에서 함께 모인 건 이번이 처음 아닌가요 ?
-You're right. -Is that so?
-네가 옳아. -그렇습니까?
-Oh my. -The moon is so pretty.
-어머. -달이 너무 예뻐요.
-Yes, it's huge. -That's very pretty.
-네, 엄청납니다. - 정말 예쁘네요.
-Yes. -Right.
-예. -오른쪽.
Then let's all make a wish together.
그럼 우리 모두 함께 소원을 빌어 볼까요?
Woo-ju, your drinking habit is making a wish to the moon, right?
우주야, 술 버릇이 달에게 소원을 빌고 있는 거 맞지?
-You're right on. -My gosh.
-맞아요. -이럴수가.
If Woo-ju wants to do that, then let's make a wish.
우주가 그렇게 하고 싶다면 소원을 빌자.
You make wishes like that?
그런 소원을 빌어요?
Then how?
그러면 어떻게?
I'm all done.
다 끝났어요.
MARCH 2007
2007년 3월
Who are you trying to look good for?
당신은 누구에게 잘 보이려고 노력하고 있습니까?
Who do you think? The future members of the Analysis Team.
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까? 분석팀의 미래 구성원입니다.
-Aren't you excited? -Why should I be?
- 신나지 않나요? -내가 왜 그래야 합니까?
You should start looking at people
사람들을 살펴보기 시작해야 해요
other than me.
나 말고.
Good grief.
맙소사.
You should stop digging my nagging.
내 잔소리 좀 그만 파세요.
You need to share your love with these future members.
미래의 멤버들과 사랑을 나눠야 합니다 .
Let me off right over there.
바로 저쪽으로 보내주세요.
Forget it. It's a special day, so let's get our hair done.
잊어 버려. 특별한 날이니까 머리를 다듬자.
-Hello. -Yes, hello.
-안녕하세요. -네, 안녕하세요.
Recently, vitamin care is received greatly by our customers.
최근에는 비타민 케어가 고객들에게 큰 호응을 얻고 있습니다.
-What do you think? -Really?
-어떻게 생각하나요? -정말?
This is perfect for us.
이것은 우리에게 완벽합니다.
Then let's do this one.
그럼 이걸 해보자.
-Okay. -All right.
-좋아요. -괜찮은.
-We'll do this. -Sure.
- 우리가 할게요. -확신하는.
Do you drink a lot?
술을 많이 마시나요?
How did you know?
어떻게 알았나요?
This is a care routine we recommend to those who drink often
술을 자주 마시는 분들에게 추천드리는 케어 루틴입니다.
and have bad blood circulation.
그리고 혈액순환이 안좋아요.
For those who are stressed and need to be refreshed.
스트레스를 받고 리프레시가 필요한 분들을 위한 제품입니다 .
That already feels nice.
벌써 기분이 좋네요.
-Chief Kook. -Yes?
- 국과장님. -예?
Does it feel good?
느낌 좋니?
It feels very refreshing.
매우 상쾌한 느낌입니다.
Ha-young, you should do it too.
하영아 너도 해봐야지
Someone said a person's heart is the most difficult thing to fathom.
누군가는 사람의 마음이 가장 가늠하기 어렵다고 말했습니다.
But there are those who must do such difficult work.
그런데 이렇게 어려운 일을 해야만 하는 사람들이 있습니다 .
On top of that,
게다가,
they must fathom the hearts of criminals, not just any old person.
그들은 노인뿐만 아니라 범죄자들의 마음도 헤아려야 합니다 .
At times, among countless numbers of criminals,
때때로 수많은 범죄자들 사이에서
they must put up a fight
그들은 싸워야 합니다
to read the minds of serial killers, who are the worst evil of them all.
가장 악한 연쇄살인범의 마음을 읽는 것입니다 .
And these people are none other than you.
그리고 이 사람들은 바로 당신입니다.
Someone once said an angel is only a hair different from a devil.
누군가 천사는 악마 와 머리카락이 다를 뿐이라고 말한 적이 있습니다.
Most minds that live an ordinary life,
평범한 삶을 살아가는 대부분의 마음은
and the most atrocious minds that commit heinous murders.
그리고 극악무도한 살인을 저지르는 가장 극악무도한 정신들 .
Where did they cross their paths?
그들은 어디에서 길을 건너게 되었습니까?
What made these people so wicked?
무엇이 이 사람들을 그토록 사악하게 만들었습니까?
Our duty begins with that basic question.
우리의 의무는 바로 이 기본적인 질문에서 시작됩니다.
In this chaotic world
이 혼란스러운 세상에서
and dramatic reality,
그리고 드라마틱한 현실,
the only thing that keeps us from becoming evil
우리가 악해지는 것을 막는 유일한 것은
might be our ability to touch people's hearts.
사람들의 마음을 감동시키는 것은 우리의 능력일지도 모릅니다 .
I hope your duty becomes another chance
너의 의무가 또 다른 기회가 되길
to revisit the preciousness and the importance of that ability.
그 능력의 소중함 과 중요성을 다시 한번 생각해 보세요.
I hope you will
그렇게하길 바래
learn to embrace your own hearts.
자신의 마음을 포용하는 법을 배우십시오.
Through this duty,
이 임무를 통해,
I also had the chance
나에게도 기회가 있었다
to have priceless experiences
값진 경험을 하기 위해
and to realize these important values in life.
삶의 중요한 가치를 깨닫는 것입니다 .
APPOINTMENT CEREMONY 1ST CRIMINAL BEHAVIORAL ANALYSTS
제1차 범죄행동분석가 임명식
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
Today, we interviewed the first profiler in Korea,
오늘은 국내 최초의 프로파일러를 인터뷰했습니다 .
Captain Song Ha-young of the Behavioral Analysis Team.
행동분석팀 송하영 대위
Is there anything you would like to say
하고 싶은 말이 있나요
before we wrap up the interview?
인터뷰를 마무리하기 전에요?
Well…
그럼???
We have yet to catch the culprit in the Daesung Serial Murder Case.
아직 대성연쇄살인사건의 범인을 잡지 못했습니다 .
And if he's watching the show right now,
그가 지금 이 프로그램을 보고 있다면
I would like to say this to him.
그에게 이 말을 전하고 싶습니다.
Science is making progress day by day.
과학은 나날이 발전하고 있습니다.
And there's no perfect crime in this world.
그리고 이 세상에 완전범죄는 없습니다 .
So you'll never get away with this.
그러니 당신은 결코 이 일에서 벗어날 수 없을 것입니다.
GYEONGGI INVESTIGATION HEADQUARTERS OF SERIAL MISSING WOMEN CASE
경기연쇄 실종여성사건수사 본부
THANKS TO THE IMPROVEMENT OF FORENSIC SCIENCE AFTER THE 2000S,
2000년대 이후 법의학의 발전에 힘입어
WE'RE ABLE TO CATCH SERIAL KILLERS EARLY
연쇄 살인범을 조기 에 잡을 수 있습니다
BUT THERE ARE HUNDREDS OF VICTIMS OF VIOLENT CRIMES EVERY YEAR
그러나 매년 수백 명의 폭력 범죄로 인한 피해자가 발생합니다
WE WOULD LIKE TO PRAY FOR THE SOULS OF THE VICTIMS
우리는 희생자들의 영혼을 위해 기도하고 싶습니다
SACRIFICED IN THESE BRUTAL CRIMES
이 잔혹한 범죄로 희생되었습니다
AND OFFER OUR CONDOLENCES TO THE BEREAVED FAMILY
그리고 유족들에게 조의를 표합니다.
MAY OUR SOCIETY BE SAFE AND PROTECTED FROM CRIMES
우리 사회가 범죄로부터 안전하고 보호되기를 바랍니다
MAY PEOPLE PAY ATTENTION TO THE VICTIMS
사람들이 피해자들에게 주의를 기울이기를 바랍니다
AND BEREAVED FAMILIES AS THEY'RE NEGLECTED THE MOST
그리고 가장 무시당하는 유족들
THROUGH THE DARKNESS PROFILING REPORT
어둠 속에서 프로파일링 보고서
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING THROUGH THE DARKNESS
THROUGH THE DARKNESS를 시청해 주셔서 감사합니다.